Finding Aid for the Maud Allan Papers, 1910-1934 LSC.2038
UCLA Library Special Collections
Maud Allan papers
1910-1934
UCLA Library Special Collections
Allan, Maud
LSC.2038
1 linear feet ( 2 boxes and 1 oversize box.)
Maud Allan (1883-1956) was a interpretive dancer. She made her performing debut in Vienna (1903) and was best known for her solo performance in The vision of Salome (1908). She toured India (1913), Southeast Asia (1913 and 1923), South America (1919-1920), and the U.S. The collection contains manuscripts, photographs, postcard albums, books, ephemera, and a scrapbook related to Allan's life and career.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
PORTIONS OF THIS COLLECTION HAVE BEEN DIGITIZED. Please consult digital facsimiles instead of originals. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Ifan Kyrle Fletcher, purchase, 1965.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942303093606533
Biography
Maud Allan was born in Toronto, Canada in 1883; raised in San Francisco, California; performing debut, Vienna, 1903; best known solo performance, The vision of Salome, 1908; toured India in 1913, Southeast Asia in 1913 and 1923, South America from 1919 to 1920, and the U.S.; had a school in England beginning in 1928; died in Los Angeles, October 7, 1956.
Scope and Content
Collection contains manuscripts, photographs, postcard albums, books, ephemera, and a scrapbook related to the life and career of Canadian-born interpretive dancer Maud Allan. Correspondence in a letter book represents correspondence by her agent, W. Angus MacLeod. Some books in the collection were presentation copies made to Allan, while others are from her library. The postcard album is made up of postcards sent to Allan.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Manuscripts, ephemera, and books (Box 1).
Photograph albums and books (Box 2).
Scrapbook and postcard album (Box 3).
Online Items Available
Portions of this collection have been digitized and are available online: Maud Allan Papers (5 items).
Women dancers -- Archives.; Allan, Maud--Archives; MacLeod, W. Angus -- Correspondence
- Ephemera
  - Maud Allan and her art. England, 1911.; 12 leaves. 26 cm. A dance program. (Box 1)
- Manuscripts
  - Letter book of Maud Allan's India and Far East tour. v.p., 1913-14.; 179 leaves. 25 cm. Carbon copies of holograph correspondence. Bound in grey cardboard cover. (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Most of the correspondence is by her agent, W. Angus MacLeod.
- Presentation Copies to/or Books Owned by Maud Allan
  - Plays of gods and men; The tents of Arabs; The laughter of the Gods; The queen's enemies; and A night at an inn. New York: G.P. Putnam's Son's []., 1917 (Box 1)
  - Lady precious stream. An old Chinese play done into English according to its traditional style. With a preface by Lascelles Abercrombie. London: Methuen & Company, Limited []., 1934 (Box 1)
  - Rhythm, music and education. Translated from the French by Harold Rubinstein. New York: G.P. Putnam's Sons, 1921. (Box 1)
  - The sunken bell. A fairy play in five acts. By Gerhart Hauptmann. Freely rendered into English verse by Charles Henry Meltzer. New York: Doubleday, Page & Company []., 1899 (Box 1)
  - Dance as an art form. Its history and development. New York: A.S. Barnes and Company, 1933. (Box 1)
  - Margaret Morris dancing. A book of pictures by Fred Daniels. With an introduction and outline of her method by Margaret Morris. London, Kegan Paul, Trench, Trubner & Company, Limited []. (Box 1)
  - The unchastened woman. A comedy. New York: Frederick A. Stokes, Company []., 1916 (Box 2)
  - Mimes et ballet grecs. Paris: Librairie Léon Vanier, éditeur, 1908. (Box 2)
- Oversize Packages
  - 1 postcard album (several of the postcards are addressed to Maud Allan). (Box 3)
  - 1 scrapbook album (compiled of postcards gathered while on a personal tour of Europe in )., 1927 (Box 3)
- Photograph Albums
  - 1 album of photgraphs of Maud Allan and friends., Bound in green cover. (Box 2)
  - 1 album of photographs of Maud Allan and friends in Africa., Bound in black cover. (Box 2)
  - 1 album of photographs of Maud Allan at grave of Cecil Rhodes., Bound in black cover. (Box 2)
  - 1 album of photographs of Maud Allan and friends on their India and Far mast tour. Photographs taken by J.W. Mitchell., Bound in black cover. (Box 2)